"1959 Hong Kong"
"Ip Man's older son was
studying in Foshan."
"Ip Man lived in Hong Kong with
his wife and younger son."
"He taught Wing Chun and
promoted the martial arts."
Master Ip
Morning!
So early?
Master Ip, it's me.
You don't recognise me?
Siu Long
When I was little I asked
to study with you.
You said: grow up first.
Please take me as a disciple.
Why should I accept you?
Because I will be your
greatest disciple.
Why are you so sure?
Because I'm fast.
How fast?
Not fast enough, kid.
Can you be faster?
Not bad.
But did you really
kick the water
or only think you did?
Licorice, licorice
Come on, somebody are fighting
Fight! Fight!
Come on.
Cheung Fong of Wing Chun.
Ip Ching of Wing Chun.
Stop! Stop fighting.
I told you two not to fight.
Big trouble. It's
not the first time.
Break the shell, then
remove the yolk.
What's with the ring?
The old folks say
that adding silver
helps with bruising.
So, why were you fighting today?
It's always over whose
kungfu is best.
I should've kept an eye on them.
What a fight, they
really got hurt.
It's Ching's fault.
He's so naughty.
So, where is this boy's father?
Cheung Fong is new here.
His dad picks him up quite late.
Fong, what does your dad do?
Is he always so busy?
Rickshaw puller.
Sorry, sorry.
- Sorry, Miss Wong.
- Master Ip
I was busy at the kungfu school
so I'm late.
Let me see.
Ah Ching, what's this about?
Both kids were at fault in fact.
So I wanted all the
family heads here.
Right. ls Fong's dad here yet?
I need to apologise to them.
No, like you he's late.
No problem, work comes first.
Don't eat that.
- You can't eat it.
- Put it down
The boy is hungry.
Miss Wong, how about this -
we'll give them dinner first.
Just let his father know,
- Okay?
- Okay.
Okay, Wing-sing?
Of course
Fong, have dinner with us, okay?
Take your book bag.
- Take care.
- We're off.
Thank you
- Very kind, Master Ip
- Sorry to trouble you,
- Thank you, Mrs Ip.
- Bye
Bye
Ah Fong, eat up, don't be shy.
Yeah,Fong!
Make yourself at home, eat.
Eat up.
Darling, the fish is delicious.
Cheung Fong -
not bad.
Who taught you?
My dad. Can you fight?
A little.
I'm Cheung Fong's dad.
Is my son there, please?
Yes he is.
Nice to meet you, Mr Cheung.
Please, come in.
Fong, your dad's here.
Master.
Disciple
Tell me what went on today.
The kids were
naughty and fought.
They'll learn in time.
Come here, Ah Ching.
Disciple
Aren't you going to apologise?
Ah Ching is at fault too.
Ip Ching, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, Cheung Fong.
Shake hands.
Now you're friends.
I've taken you out of your way.
I apologise, Mr Cheung.
Good to meet you, Master Ip.
I saw Fong working
the wooden man.
He's good - he's
been taught well.
Too kind.
But it's late.
You should rest.
I'll see you off.
Master
Uncle Ip has a wooden man too
Do you know him?
Yes.
Uncle Ip is very famous.
But one day
I'll be more famous.
Which of you
is better at kungfu?
Who do you think?
You of course!
Let's go.
Give me a look... does it hurt?
No
It's about to start.
Hurry! Hurry!
Bet on the winner.
- I told you, follow my lead.
- Great.
One at a time!
Bigger bets, bigger wins.
Move, outta the way.
Cheung Tin Chi, Cheung Tin Chi
How are you doing?
Come on, come on.
Brother Sang, Brother Sang.
- The boss is here.
- What?
The boss is here.
Not bad, kid.
Go.
Hit hard, fast.
Hey boss.
Come on.
- Wait here, I'll be right back.
- Okay.
Boss -
don't worry,
I've got it under control.
Two week's money.
- Open it.
- Okay.
You did good.
- Thank you.
- What about that other business?
The school?
No problem. Give me one month.
No. Two weeks.
C'mon...
Okay, I love a challenge.
Deal you
Remember, I want that school.
The rest means
nothing without it.
Yes. Understood.
What kind of kungfu is that?
Wing Chun.
It's really powerful.
Martial artists come
here every day.
We chat, drink tea...
Each school has its own table.
Master Tin.
- Master Chan, a rising star -
- Master Tin.
He has a lot of students.
Master Chan.
Now this table is amazing -
the best of the best.
It's my table.
Master Tin.
Just kidding.
The real champions sit there -
That's the Wing Chun table.
Master Tin.
Ah Lik, where's your master?
There he is.
Master Ip.
Master Tin, have you eaten?
No - your treat?
Of course!
You know Master Ip, of course?
- Master Ip, hello. I'm Lee.
- How do you do.
- Mr Lee.
- Hello.
Lee is a reporter, and keen
to write about the martial arts.
He'll take photos too.
- Great.
- Okay with you, Master Ip?
- Of course.
- Thank you so much.
- Master Lee, right here.
- Too kind.
- Ip Man, the center seat.
- No, no.
- It's yours.
- No, really.
No it's fitting, sit down.
Master Ip, telephone.
I'll take that if it's okay.
Sure
we'll save your seat.
We'll wait.
Hello?
Did you forget our date?
Wasn't it for...
For today.
Today“.
Oh, I'll rush right over.
I've been waiting an hour.
The dancing is almost finished.
So don't bother.
Just pick up Ah
Ching from school.
Oh, I'm in trouble.
- Master Ip, please.
- Sit down.
Here, the middle seat.
- Okay, I give in.
- And why not.
Look sharp, eyes
front, hold still!
Ready“.
One, two, three.
Master Ip,
- Hello.
- you're here for your son?
Where's your wife?
She's busy today.
And you're not?
It's okay...
Master Ip, you look
younger by the day.
Must be his wife's cooking -
such tender meat.
Such a lucky couple.
Master Ip
Mr Cheung
- hello.
- Hello.
- Picking up your son?
- Yes.
Oh,
this medicine helps
with bruises.
It's for your son.
Thank you, that's so nice.
How is Fong?
He's fine.
I'm glad.
Master Ip -
I hear you studied
with Chan Wah Shun, yes?
Yes.
So we're both from the school
of Foshan's Grandmaster
Leung Jan.
So we are truly
brothers-in-arms.
I heard that
Chan used fist and pole
better than swords and feet.
Is that true?
Having strengths
and weaknesses -
It's normal.
How about you, Master Ip?
I'm just a dabbler.
If we have the chance,
let's have a friendly match.
Sure.
BYE, Miss!
Be careful.
Master.
Disciple -
What did you learn today?
- Mathematics.
- Mathematics?
Chinese, English.
How'd you do?
- Did you behave?
- That's all.
Yes.
D'you go to school?
NU?-.
Principal
this man is asking for you.
How may I help you?
- Hey - Move it!
- What's going on?
- Sit, don't move.
- Don't move.
- Looking at me?
Fatty, calm down!
How can I talk over your noise?
So sorry, sir, we
gave you a fright.
- What's going on?
- Come, sit down.
Make room.
Don't be afraid.
You're a scholar,
I'm a gentleman.
We're reasonable people.
This is prime real estate.
Sell your school to me.
It's a fair offer.
"Contract of Sale"
I'm not selling.
Won't you even read it first?
Go on.
I'm not selling.
Educated people are a pain.
They don't do as told.
Watch out, Boss.
What's going on?
They're forcing me
to sell the school.
Think I don't know kungfu?
Ip Man, it's a business deal-
keep your damn nose out of it.
Hello, this is Chi
yan Primary School.
We need police here right now.
Some thugs are causing trouble.
- Cut it out.
- Let him go.
Let my boss go
or I'll whack her.
- Let my boss go, now!
- Let him go
- Do it!
Don't rush, take your time.
Start from the beginning.
The three just barged in
and began smashing things up.
Hong Kong seems prosperous
but really it's a mess.
More wealth means more crime.
We're like Cyclops
and his wife -
can't always keep an eye on her.
Truth is, we're understaffed
- and insanely busy.
- You're right
Hongkong's crime
rate is going up.
It seems pretty lawless.
No, we still have law.
Call the police
and we come.
We'll crack this case.
The bastards won't
get away with it.
Yes, yes.
We're relying on you, Sgt. Po.
Of course, it's my duty.
But Master Ip
you know the score.
The police can't keep
watch here all day.
We need your help.
Tell people to be careful.
- I will.
- Anything happens, call us.
- I'll come straightaway. Okay?
- Great, thank you.
- You're welcome. Let's go, men.
- Yes, sir.
- See you.
- Take care.
Bye.
Ip Man,
you piss me off.
I'm gonna do you slowly.
David.
Brother Sang
Chain up the school tonight.
Don't worry.
It'll be okay.
It's okay.
Don't worry -
the school won't shut.
Principal!
Miss Wong
Master Ip
Miss Wong -
what's going on?
It was like this
when I got here.
Will they demolish the school?
How will our kids
get an education?
Dad, open the gate.
I'll help you - careful.
You're really strong.
Can't I be skinny and strong?
Sure.
I'm big but not that strong.
My name is Hui Lik.
They call me Miss Wong.
Call me if you need help.
Come in,
Morning, granny.
Morning, Principal.
Morning, Miss Wong.
Morning.
Master
Let's
They'll be back for sure.
Then wait here for them.
Okay.
Tonight we're staying here.
Good.
Miss Wong, funny
meeting you again.
Yes, can I help you?
No-.
May I ask, do you
have a boyfriend?
No-.
Great.
Would you like a boyfriend?
Haven't thought about it.
Don't get me wrong...
but it's dark.
You shouldn't walk home alone.
I'm sorry.
Master Ip
Hello, Miss Wong.
We've put you to a
lot of trouble.
It's nothing.
Is my disciple
giving you trouble?
No, Master Ip.
Not at all.
He kindly offered
to see me home.
That's all it was, Master.
Why don't you see me home then?
Okay.
Hey, let's see Master
Ip home tonight.
Sure, it's pretty quiet.
Okay.
Master Ip, you did a
lot for us today.
You should get some rest.
I'm fine.
I didn't have any other plans.
HEY
Hurry.
You guys, over there!
- Help, Master Ip!
- Take him.
Help!
Protect Miss Wong!
Okay?
Yup, but we're definitely
seeing you home.
UP there!
Okay.
Help!
Move.
Let's go, men.
We checked everywhere;
the fire's out.
Make sure there's
no live embers.
Okay.
- Go double-check.
- Okay.
Master,
the fire's extinguished.
But nothing's left but ash.
Principal,
are you okay?
I'm fine.
But I underestimated
those thugs.
Lucky you and your
men were here.
- It was nothing.
- Thank you so much, Master Ip.
Mr Cheung,
thank goodness you were there.
I was just passing by
I've finally seen
your Wing Chun.
It's as good as they say.
People are too nice.
If all's Well
I'll get back to work.
Bye.
The people want me to stay
and help guard the area.
It's arson, aren't
the cops involved?
Yes, why wouldn't they be?
'Fatty' Po says they'll
crack the case.
We've no reason to
doubt his word.
That's good.
But they can't give
24-hour protection.
So
for a few nights
I might be out late.
Should I cook dinner then?
Sure,
what'll I eat otherwise?
They can't do it without you?
It's not that.
But if I can help I will.
It's working.
Then do me a favour
- turn it off.
So sorry, so sorry -
I was having dinner.
Come in, have a look.
Come, have a look.
The place has great fengshui.
It's an oasis of calm.
So the Wall's a bit chipped -
you can sweep it clean.
Disciple
I'll open my kungfu school here.
You'll have lots of
classmates then.
Is that good?
Great! I'll be able to practice
here and here and here!
How much is a month's rent?
HK$180. Water and
electricity included.
I'll think it over. Thank you.
Sir, the rent is negotiable.
You pull a rickshaw?!
And you're going
to run a school?
AS if!
- You're wasting my time.
- Where to, boss?
Home.
Loser
Sir, my report on the
school arson case.
Then wait here for them.
Sign and I'll follow up.
Not necessary. I'm handling it.
Don't be silly,
it's a small case.
Too small for you, sir.
Let me handle it, okay?
Do you understand Chinese?
The investigation
into the school-
I will take care of it
because I am in charge.
So piss off.
Get
out
Yes, sir.
What the hell-
you blind?
What's it to you?
You own the road?
Idiot.
- Here comes more.
- You at it again?
Brother.
Thanks.
When I was at tea this morning
people were saying
we'd become security guards.
Oh, don't worry about it.
Master Ip doesn't
listen to gossip.
Who said it anyway?
Lots of people.
Would you recognise them?
Mantis?
How can I help you?
I often have pain in my abdomen.
Do you have anything for it?
Yes,
Crow And Phoenix Pills.
They help circulate.
Okay, I'll have a packet.
- Ip Man.
- Hi
- Why didn't you tell me
- Master Tin, have a seat.
What happened?
Have a seat.
They're saying at the tea house
you've become a security guard.
That's so insulting.
I bet it's that little
bastard's doing.
Have some tea.
I rue the day I made
Ah Sang a disciple.
He uses my kungfu
to do awful things.
It's disgraceful!
He shames my school!
See -
how could I tell you?
Well I'm telling you -
I'll teach him a lesson!
I'm going after him.
Master Tin.
Master Tin, calm down.
Uncle Chan, I'll pay for this.
Master Tin
Master Tin.
Let Sgt. Po handle it.
Too late for that.
I'll take care of this myself.
That little shit
owes me respect.
He's no longer your
responsibility.
It's true that he left my school
but I'm still his teacher.
Don't fret, I'll be fine.
Stop. What d'ya want?
I'm looking for Ma King Sang
I'm his teacher. Call him out.
Sgt.
Ah-Lik, where's Master Ip?
Too late for that.
Master Tin was really furious.
Not sure why.
Master Tin?
Now what?
Why are you here,
Master Ip?
So I see my teacher.
What's it to you?
Master.
Sang,
leave Master Ip out of this.
It's my idea to come here.
Stop causing so much trouble.
Leave those people
alone, give it up.
I always taught you
to do the right thing.
Look at yourself.
Know what you look like?
Dirty money and a
pack of thugs -
really grand, you are!
Think about it - if
you didn't pay them
would they still be there?
When you're around,
they bow and scrape.
Behind your back
they call you the foreign
devil's flunkey.
What? You want to fight me?
So I'm a flunkey -
A flunkey with money
is as good as a king.
And you?
A poor teacher, so pure -
you have to repair
umbrellas to eat.
Does that feel good?
You can't eat purity, can you?
Ask yourself-
Which of your students
still remember you?
Which still care about you?
All of them,
they're with me now.
Bastard!
You'd stab me?
You thug! You want to kill me?
Hurt me and you won't escape.
Men, over here!
- Free Ah Sang!
- Don't worry about me.
Attack!
Fight, brothers!
C'mon!
Free Ah Sang!
Police, stop it!
Get back, get back.
Get back
Go home.
Move and I'll shoot.
You playing with me?
Get out.
Say What?
Now you give the orders?
Know who owns this patch?
Gonna shoot me? Well?
What'll you tell
your captain then?
Shut up or I'll arrest you.
I'll seal off this whole place.
See what you tell
your boss then!
Don't believe me?
Just try me, you bastard!
What'll you do about the school?
Sang's boss has my
captain in his pocket.
The two foreign devils
are in cahoots.
It's hopeless. The
school is doomed.
Fatty, I trust you
because you're not
like other cops.
But one word from a foreigner
and you drop the case?
It's not that, it's pointless.
So you didn't
arrest the arsonist
or look after the
people and the kids.
And now my disciples
are doing your work for you.
What else can I do?
Master Ip, you're a
fighter, not a god.
Too late for that.
You guard the school
day and night-
but for how long?
You know foreign
devils run Hongkong.
The world's not fair.
But moral standards
apply to all.
The ruler isn't always
a superior person.
And the ruled isn't
always inferior.
The world doesn't
belong to the rich
or even the powerful
but to those of pure heart.
Have you thought
of the children?
All that we do,
they're watching.
We need to be good role models.
All that we do,
is not for today
but for tomorrow.
"Toss it if you don't want it."
"Please sew on the button."
Mrs Ip, my initial diagnosis
is to suspect a tumor.
It's not very encouraging.
But we'll learn more
once we have the full report.
Try not to worry too much.
Master Ip
Master Ip, Master Ip
You work so hard.
Master Ip, We all pitched
in for the soup.
- Enjoy it - Thank you
You're here night and day.
You need sustenance.
Where are your disciples?
They should have some too.
Thank you, thank you.
I had told you the
blue one is better,
but you still buy the red one.
Great, great, another win.
So many fights -
what's the deal?
Need money?
It's a living.
I need to eat too.
That time at the school,
you hurt my men.
You owe me.
How much do I owe?
It's not about that.
I admire you.
I wanna be your friend.
Sang, what's this about?
I'm talking about
the kind of friendship
that pushes another
mam to the wall.
I'm buying a man's hand here.
You've so many men -
why do you need me?
Because he knows kungfu
and so do you.
And you fight well.
And if I say no?
Then go elsewhere for a crust.
The blue? Hand it over.
You won? Give it here.
Ah Sang -
That money -
I want it all.
How many more days of this?
You're up?
I didn't want to wake you.
Just a few more days.
When will you eat at home again?
Tonight.
I'll come back earlier.
Are you okay?
Well...
- Hello - Hello? Master Ip?
Yes, who's this?
Kowloon Hospital.
What is it?
Master Tin has
been badly wounded
and he wants to see you.
Okay, I'll be right there.
I made the call.
Thank you.
Let's get to work.
Very good.
Go play.
Luckily it's only a hand injury.
It could've been a lot worse.
Thank you.
Ah Sang sent him for sure.
As a teacher, I'm
a total failure.
Let's get some!
Yes, this one!
Kids,
I have some cartoon slides
want to see them?
It's free.
C'mon.
Hey!
- Hurry - What're you doing?
- Help, help - Help, me
Hey!
Take him
What're you doing?
- Enjoy - Help me.
You've got two hours.
Get the principal
to the shipyard
or I sell the kids into slavery.
How'd you know I
was in hospital?
You told them to call me.
No I didn't.
You didn't?
Mrs Ip, where's Master Ip?
What is it?
Tell me what happened?
Master Ip!
What is it, Miss Wong?
A man abducted Ching,
Fong and other kids.
What?
If the principal
doesn't go to see him,
he'll sell the
children into slavery.
Hurry, find the principal,
tell Sgt. Po.
Great.
I want the principal
and you bring a pole.
Just great.
And the principal?
On his way.
First let the kids go.
Okay?
Dad,Dad!
Shut up!
Son, don't be afraid.
I'm here.
Ah, so this is your son?
Lucky. I was hoping to get him.
Let him out.
Stand straight.
Shush.
Calm down,
kid, come here.
Ah Sang,
the kids aren't to blame.
Don't mess with them, okay?
How am I messing with them?
I'm giving him an apple.
Don't be afraid,
have some apple.
Just
tell Dad to put down the pole.
Then we can talk.
Ching, don't be afraid.
Put down the pole.
Act like you mean it.
On your knees.
Kowtow.
Master Ip?
Hey -
What're you doing here?
There's no fight today.
You took my boy.
Master! Master!
Help me!
Ah Fong
So he's your boy -
Sorry. He's one of
ours - let him go.
Lucky it was me who took him.
Anything could've happened.
Leave it alone. Go!
Ip Man,
you're a good fighter, yes?
Can you take on ten men?
Don't say I never
gave you a chance.
One against ten...
or say eleven.
With every punch you land
I'll give him a piece to eat.
Master, they still
have my friends.
Why are you back?
To pick the kids up from school.
Bastard.
Move.
Over here.
Get him!
Another step and I'll kill him.
Dad!
Bite him.
What the...?!
Go!
Grab the kid, hurry.
Over there, quick!
Dad!
Dad! Dad!
David, don't just stand there!
Grab that kid.
Dad!
Kneel. Don't move.
Kneel
Don't move.
- Hear me?
- I'm not with them.
Don't move! No one move!
Police. Don't move!
No one move!
Go in and take photos.
Don't move!
All those guys over there.
They'll make great news photos.
Great headline material.
Get 'em all.
I said don't move!
Mama
Mama!
Ah Ching!
There was trouble at the school.
They abducted Ah Ching.
I'm so sorry, Wing Sing.
It's my fault
I was wrong.
It's my fault.
It won't happen again,
okay?
Go wash your face.
Okay.
Good kid.
It's all my fault.
Don't cry.
Darling, I'm so afraid.
It's all right now.
But I might not be.
What do you mean?
The doctor said...
I probably...
have cancer.
The black spots
indicate cancer cells.
These are tumors.
The cancer has spread too widely
for us to be able to operate.
Is it curable?
Normally, we'd
prescribe medicines
but at this stage,
they're unlikely to
get it under control.
Doctor, how much time do I have?
Maybe six months.
I'll get you more rice.
Just half.
Don't worry, you're safe.
The police are on your side.
Every day there's a new
story in the paper.
Abducted children,
people being thrown
from their homes.
My boss is unhappy.
And when my boss is unhappy,
I am unhappy-
So-
for the time being all this
nefarious vice and corruption
that you so love to
engage yourself in -
you'll have to take a hiatus.
Otherwise...
"WING CHUN'S IP MAN HELPS
POLICE RESCUE CHILDREN"
Frankie,
I can't protect you.
Whatever you say.
Yes.
Well, Frankie,
these chats are
always a pleasure.
Cheerio.
Hey Boss!
This Thai guy's incredible.
Elbows, knees,
fists - all great.
Really fierce.
Put it up
It's my mistake, Boss.
I just meant to give
the principal a scare
Not to create such a mess.
Ip Man - it's all his fault.
I'm sorry.
I don't ever want to
see your face again.
Fuck off!
Ip Man.
Finish him off!
Get out.
Want any tea?
Listen, things
have quieted down.
I'm not expecting more trouble.
But-
the foreign devils
can't be trusted.
Ah Sang's boss has
it out for you.
Be careful.
So smart.
Mom, look!
You want me, I'm here.
What do you want?
So you're Ip Man?
You're the best
fighter in China.
Interesting.
Okay, let's deal.
It seems your Wing
Chun is the fastest
so fast you're invincible.
Let's see whose
fists are fastest.
Yours?
Or mine?
Three minutes.
If you last
I'll let you be.
Hey, how ya doin'?
I want my balloon back.
Let it go, don't worry about it.
We'll get a new one, okay?
A new balloon.
Madame -
here's my rent.
I always said you'd come good!
Best of luck! You'll
be raking it in!
Great! I can practice
Wing Chun here!
Master - respect!
Respect!
Sir, you teach Wing Chun?
You must know Ip Man, yes?
Look, today's newspaper -
he's in the news.
He's so impressive.
I bet you two are great friends.
Introduce me sometime.
Here's the key. I'll leave you.
Don't forget to introduce me!
Did you write this?
"WING CHUN'S IP MAN HELPS
POLICE RESCUE CHILDREN"
Yes.
My name is Cheung Tin Chi.
I'm also a Wing Chun fighter.
Can you write about me too?
I've seen Ip Man's kungfu
it's not authentic Wing Chun.
I'll challenge him
to a public match.
All the kungfu schools
respect Ip Man's Wing Chun.
Sure, I'll write something.
But we'll see if the
kungfu world...
will think you're qualified
to publicly challenge Ip Man?
Have a seat, Master.
Got your camera?
Nice tea today.
Cheung of Wing Chun.
A friendly match?
Who do you think - ?
"CHEUNG TIN CHI BURSTS
ONTO KUNGFU SCENE"
"WING CHUN TRIUMPHANT CHEUNG
TIN CHl'S FAME SPREADS"
"NEW KUNGFU KING:
CHEUNG TIN CHI"
Now - am I qualified?
Sure.
Master Cheung is coming.
Congratulation, Master Cheung.
Eyes front, please.
Mr Wong, thanks you
for your support.
I admire a fighter with
guts and ambition.
If I can be of help,
just say the word.
Thank you
Master Cheung,
you're fighting everyone
and take along photographers.
You don't worry
people will talk?
I know lots of people think
I'm a show-off,
that I act superior.
But in kungfu
you need to establish
who's tops.
And I want to tell people this:
Ip Man
can't represent Wing Chun.
Gentlemen:
I hereby announce:
I'm challenging Ip
Man to a fight!
"Grandmaster of Wing Chun"
Extra, extra.
Wing Chun vs. Wing Chun
- Get your paper.
- I'll have one.
"CHEUNG TIN CHI
CHALLENGES IP MAN"
"WHOSE IS THE TRUE WING CHUN?"
Darling, it's so ridiculous.
It's like the joke about Ah Mo.
He's dining with friends.
He says:
We're all henpecked.
Want proof?
If your wife is the
boss, sit over there.
All the men, heads
held low, went over.
Only Mo stayed where he was.
They said,
wow, Mo, you're The Man!
Know what Mo said? He said,
well, my wife told me:
Don't sit in crowded places.
Funny, right?
Are you scared of your wife?
Sometimes.
Next.
Are you Cheung Wing Sing?
Why'd God make women
pretty but dumb?
They're pretty
so men will like them.
They're dumb
so they will like men.
Look, someone's
challenging Ip Man -
- When?
- Next month, on the 15th.
Harder.
Relax the shoulders, punch fast.
This way, Master Cheung.
I want to sit there.
"Master Ip"
Excuse me.
Master Ip, what're
you doing here?
I'm looking for Mr Chan.
You want to learn to dance?
I dance better than him.
I'll teach you.
And you can teach me kungfu.
Sure. Now?
Okay.
When will you accept
me as a disciple?
You got it all wrong.
I didn't say I
wouldn't accept you.
I didn't open the door
so you'd leave.
Thank you.
Welcome.
Wing Chun vs. Wing Chun
- who's the real deal?
It's an historic
day for Wing Chun.
It will be like a
battle of dragons!
Yes! ls Ip Man the
greater fighter?
Or is Cheung Tin
Chi fiercer still?
Who represents the
true Wing Chun?
Today at 3:00pm.
The contest will begun.
We wait with bated breath.
Sgt. Po. Sgt. Po!
- Brother - Master Tin
- Ah-Lik - Where's Master Ip?
No idea!
What's the problem?
Maybe he's lost?
Relax, Ip Man won't let us down.
I'm here.
It's 3:00pm. Why
isn't Ip Man here?
It's time.
Look, it's three.
Where's your master?
Gentlemen -
the match was
scheduled for 3:00pm.
Since Ip Man has
failed to show up
I hereby announce
the victor and true
spirit of Wing Chun
Cheung Tin Chi.
Dad! Dad!
We won! We won!
Maybe he's stuck in traffic?
And this makes you
a grandmaster?
Master Cheung, what
do have to say
about Ip Man's no-show today?
To mess with classic Wing Chun
is to lose the
forefathers' vision.
It's wrong both now
and into the future as well.
Our forefathers don't need worry
about the form's future.
I believe Master Ip
understands this.
So he chose to
forfeit the fight.
This is also an act
of great merit.
From today,
I, Cheung Tin Chi
will lead the true Wing Chun
to a glorious future.
- Bravo.
- True Wing Chun.
What'd you say?
You've no right to that claim -
you aren't qualified
to fight my master!
- Settle down, stop.
- Stop.
Wing Sing! Wing Sing!
Please, someone
call an ambulance!
Mr Ip, her condition
is worsening.
She needs to stay in
hospital for a bit.
Well? Feeling any better?
When can we go home?
The doctor said it's better
for you to stay here.
You need rest.
85... no, you're right.
Give the letter to Cheung Fong.
Tell him to give it to his dad.
Okay.
Nurse, nurse!
What it is it, madam?
Are you in pain?
Don't worry, I'll
get the doctor.
Have some bullfrog soup -
it's good for you.
Darling -
I want a photograph with you.
You spend every day with me.
It makes me so happy.
But I could be happier.
People say:
Life belongs to you,
and it doesn't.
I didn't get it before.
But now, I'm beginning to.
You belong to yourself.
And to this family.
But to this place as well.
There are things you should do.
I don't want you
to have regrets.
I only regret not
being better to you.
But I think...
you've been great to me.
If it wasn't for my sickness,
would you have taken
the challenge?
Yes.
That's the Ip Man I love.
I've taken the liberty
of setting the date with him.
I haven't heard you
practice in ages.
Will you let me hear
that sound again?
Wing Chun,
Cheung Tin Chi.
Ip Man.
- Ip Ching, the back way - Okay.
I recognise that I'm defeated.
There's nothing more important
than the love of
those by your side.
"Ip Man's wife Cheung Wing Sing"
"passed away in
1960 from cancer."
"Ip Man taught Ip Ching Wing Chun.
Martial arts guided his life."
"Ip Man became a Grandmaster."
"Wing Chun has flourished,
generation after generation,"
"spreading across the world."